CHAD LITTLE

♥ Vermilion, Ohio, US 🗷 chadjlittle@me.com 🛘 619-807-6848 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/chadlittle

SUMMARY

Product Owner with 19 years of extensive experience in developing and managing digital products. Proven ability to build and execute successful product development strategies. Demonstrated experience in working with stakeholders to ensure product success. Applying for the position of Product Owner to drive innovation and customer satisfaction.

EXPERIENCE

SVP Product Owner

Kind Lending

March 2022 - November 2022

- Served as the Product Owner, leading agile development processes to deliver valuable product features through collaborative prioritization, requirement gathering, and stakeholder engagement.
- Instituted product prioritization process based on value to deliver high-impact features 30% faster. Collaborated with stakeholders to define value and benefits, focusing teams on customer-centric development.
- · Increased Wholesale Portal's effectiveness through data-driven analysis of help desk tickets and UX solutions, reducing user issues 75%.
- Served as primary point of contact between stakeholders and teams, clarifying requirements to maximize productivity and increase developer velocity by 20%.
- Instituted formal agile processes including sprint planning and retrospectives, empowering teams to claim ownership of development processes.
- Consolidated fragmented backlogs into master list ranked by priority, increasing development team efficiency by 15%.
- Conducted market research, competitive analysis, and gathered customer feedback to identify opportunities to differentiate product from competitors.

SVP Strategic Initiatives and Product

Stearns Lending

March 2020 - September 2021

- Directed product management and digital transformation initiatives spanning customer research, cross-functional leadership, and process improvement to transform mortgage lending platforms and workflows.
- Transformed mortgage application digital platforms, closing 50+ gaps identified through customer discovery, increasing application completion rates by 25%.
- · Led cross-functional teams to deliver enhanced mobile platform, enabling over 200 loan officers to originate loans remotely, increasing productivity.
- · Instituted uniform processes across brands by conducting workflow analysis to identify redundancies, mapping unified future-state processes, and consolidating 7 fragmented systems into single platform.
- · Aligned roadmaps across brands by establishing cross-functional leadership council to foster collaboration, spearheading bi-weekly syncs, and generating executive consensus.
- Gathered actionable customer insights through quantitative surveys and qualitative user council interviews to deeply understand pain points and quantify feature requests. Implemented top requested capabilities, delighting users.

Director Digital and Sales Support

Union Bank

May 2011 - March 2020

- Pioneered Agile product development as Director of Digital and Sales Support, launching a novel digital mortgage platform that drove a 40% increase in online application volume.
- · Led cross-functional teams to build and launch MVP digital mortgage platform, replacing existing system through Agile sprints. Increased digital application volume 40% through new functionality and enhanced UX.
- · Implemented e-signature capability, reducing application turnaround time by 14 days. Improved customer

satisfaction and retention by enabling faster completion.

- Established product support help desk, creating screens share and knowledge management tools. Reduced issue resolution time for 100+ mortgage consultants by 30% through real-time video support.
- Researched industry best practices and emerging technology to differentiate platform. Balanced compliance needs with sales goals through collaborative workshops with stakeholders.

EDUCATION

MA Communication

San Diego State University · San Diego, CA · 3.92

BA Speech Communication

San Diego State University · San Diego, CA

Business of Banking

Pacific Coast Banking School · Seattle, WA

Leadership

University of Washington - Michael G. Foster School of Business · Seattle, WA

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)

Scrum Alliance

Certified Scrum Master (CSM)

Scrum Alliance

ASTD Human Performance Technology

American Society of Training and Development

Rummler Brache Process Improvement

Pritchett

INVOLVEMENT

Member, Board of Directors

Pints for Prostates · August 2013 - Present

SKILLS

Agile, Scrum, Product Management, Product Ownership, Collaboration, User Stories, Road Mapping, Leadership, Data Decision Making, Problem Solving, Data Analysis, Communication, Presentation, Clear Concise, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Strategic Tactical, Cross Functional, Implementation, Management